They weren't born in the wild... They were shipped there.
Madagascar is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Eric Darnell.
Four animal friends get a taste of the wild life when they break out of captivity at
the Central Park Zoo and wash ashore on the island of Madagascar.
Alex (voice), played by Ben Stiller.
Marty (voice), played by Chris Rock.
Melman (voice), played by David Schwimmer.
Gloria (voice), played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Julien (voice), played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Maurice (voice), played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Madagascar is a 2005 American animated survival comedy film directed by Eric Darnell and
Tom McGrath, and written by Mark Burton, Billy Frolick, Darnell and McGrath.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation and PDI/DreamWorks, the film stars the voices of Ben Stiller, Chris Rock, David Schwimmer and Jada Pinkett Smith as a quartet of
anthropomorphic animals from the Central Park Zoo who find themselves stranded on the island of Madagascar and must adjust to living in the wild.
The film features a musical score by Hans Zimmer.
It also features a cover version of "I Like to Move It" by Sacha Baron Cohen, which
has since become a recurring theme song throughout the franchise.
Madagascar was released in the United States by
DreamWorks Pictures on May 27, 2005.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the
visuals and charm but criticized the story and humor.
It was a success at the box office, grossing $558 million on a production budget
of $75 million, becoming the sixth highest-grossing film of 2005.
The success of Madagascar launched a multimedia franchise, which includes two sequels, a spin-off film, several short
films, television series and specials and a number of video games, theme park attractions and live stage shows.
The film explores themes of friendship, island, escape, africa, lion.
The tone is lighthearted.